{"test_questions": [[{"question": "What type of waveform is shown in the given circuit?", "opta": "Sine wave", "optb": "Square wave", "optc": "Triangle wave", "optd": "Sawtooth wave", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In both induction and synchronous ac motors", "opta": "the operating speed is very steady", "optb": "the stator magnetic field is stationary", "optc": "the stator magnetic field rotates", "optd": "the \"squirrel cage\" forms the rotor", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the peak-to-peak voltage of the waveform in the given circuit?", "opta": "2 V", "optb": "4 V", "optc": "6 V", "optd": "8 V", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most practical alternators generate electricity from", "opta": "a coil rotating within a magnetic field", "optb": "a magnetic field rotating around fixed windings", "optc": "a permanent magnet rotating within a varying electromagnetic field", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A half-cycle average voltage of 12 V is equal to what rms voltage?", "opta": "13.33 V", "optb": "8.48 V", "optc": "18.84 V", "optd": "7.64 V", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the instantaneous peak voltage at 250\u00b0 on a 6 V peak sine wave?", "opta": "+5.64 V", "optb": "\u20135.64 V", "optc": "+26.13 V", "optd": "\u201326.13 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Calculate the positive-going slope of the waveform in the given circuit.", "opta": "5 V/ms", "optb": "2.5 V/ms", "optc": "2.5 V/s", "optd": "5 V/s", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A rectangular wave that has a duty cycle of 50% could be called a", "opta": "\"c\" wave", "optb": "sawtooth wave", "optc": "square wave", "optd": "triangular wave", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Calculate the duty cycle of the repetitive pulse waveform in the given circuit.", "opta": "8.33%", "optb": "0%", "optc": "33.33%", "optd": "25%", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The effective value of a sine wave is equal to", "opta": "0.707 of peak voltage", "optb": "0.636 of peak voltage", "optc": "sin 45\u00b0 of peak voltage", "optd": "both 0.707 of peak voltage and sin 45\u00b0 of peak voltage", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the dc voltage of the waveform in the given circuit?", "opta": "2 V", "optb": "4 V", "optc": "6 V", "optd": "8 V", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the fourth harmonic of a fundamental frequency of 400 Hz?", "opta": "100 Hz", "optb": "4 kHz", "optc": "4 Hz", "optd": "1.6 kHz", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the peak voltage across R3 in the given circuit?", "opta": "1.2 V", "optb": "5 V", "optc": "7 V", "optd": "12 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which point is the trailing edge of the repetitive pulse waveform in the given circuit?", "opta": "Point A", "optb": "Point B", "optc": "Point C", "optd": "Point D", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A single-phase induction motor", "opta": "is self-starting", "optb": "operates at a fixed speed", "optc": "is less reliable than a three-phase synchronous motor", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the average voltage when a rectangular wave's base line voltage is 20 V, its peak-to-peak voltage is 50 V, and its duty cycle is 20%?", "opta": "26 V", "optb": "30 V", "optc": "40 V", "optd": "45 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}